I'm a designer and an educator.
أنا مصمم ومُعلم
I'm a multitasking person, and I push my students
أنا رجل متعدد الوظائف و أدفع طلابي
to fly through a very creative, multitasking design process.
ليكونوا أكثر أبداعاً من خلال عملية التصميم متعددة الوظائف
But how efficient is, really, this multitasking?
لكن ما مدى كفاءة "تعدد الوظائف"
Let's consider for a while the option of monotasking.
دعونا ننظر لوهله خيار أن يكون الشخص لديه مهمة واحدة
A couple of examples.
مجموعة من الأمثلة
Look at that.
أنظروا إلى ذلك
This is my multitasking activity result. (Laughter)
هذه نتيجة تعدد الوظائف الخاصة بي ( ضحك )
So trying to cook, answering the phone, writing SMS,
محاولة الطبخ ، الرد على الهاتف ، كتابة رسالة نصية
and maybe uploading some pictures
و تحميل بعض الصور
about this awesome barbecue.
عن هذا الشواء الرائع
So someone tells us the story about supertaskers,
أحدهم أخبرنا عن قصة الرجال الخارقين في عمل الوظائف
so this two percent of people who are able
هؤلاء 2% من البشر قادرون على
to control multitasking environment.
التحكم في بيئة تعدد الوظائف.
But what about ourselves, and what about our reality?
لكن ماذا عن أنفسنا؟ وماذا عن الحياة الطبيعية؟
When's the last time you really enjoyed
متى آخر مرة أستمتعت بها
just the voice of your friend?
بالإستماع إلى صوت صديق
So this is a project I'm working on,
هذا المشروع الذي أعمل عليه
and this is a series of front covers
وهذه سلسلة من الغطاء الأمامي
to downgrade our super, hyper —
لتخفيض إفراط -
(Laughter) (Applause)
(ضحك) (تصفيق)
to downgrade our super, hyper-mobile phones
لتخفيض إفراط إستخدام الهواتف النقالة
into the essence of their function.
للمهام الأساسية لها.
Another example: Have you ever been to Venice?
مثال آخر، هل ذهب أحدكم إلى فينيسيا من قبل؟
How beautiful it is to lose ourselves in these little streets
كم هو جميل أن نضيع في هذه الشوارع الصغيرة.
on the island.
في الجزيرة.
But our multitasking reality is pretty different,
ولكن طبيعة تعد المهام لدينا مختلفة قليلة.
and full of tons of information.
وكثير من الأطنان من المعلومات
So what about something like that
ماذا عن شئ كهذا
to rediscover our sense of adventure?
لإعادة أكتشاف روح المغامرة فينا؟
I know that it could sound pretty weird to speak about mono
أعرف أنه قد يبدو غريباً أن تتحدث عن الأحادية
when the number of possibilities is so huge,
عندما تكون أرقام الإحتمالات كبيرة جداً.
but I push you to consider the option of
لكني أسألك بأن تفكّر بخيار
focusing on just one task,
التركيز في مهمة واحدة فقط.
or maybe turning your digital senses totally off.
أو ربما إغلاق حدسك الرقمي تماماً.
So nowadays, everyone could produce his mono product.
لذلك هذه الأيام، أي وشخص يمكنه إنتاج هذا المُنتج الأحادي.
Why not? So find your monotask spot
لِم لا ؟ إذاَ أوجد منطقة مهمتك الأحادية
within the multitasking world.
في هذا العالَم المتعدد المهام
Thank you.
شكراً لكُم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)